<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | EmNets</title>
    <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>zh-Hans</language><copyright>EmNets © 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkLab</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/linklab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/linklab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;简介&#34;&gt;简介&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;物联网设备异构性加剧，物联网应用开发仍然十分困难。实验室与阿里云IoT事业部联合发起了
&lt;a href=&#34;http://linklab.tinylink.cn&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkLab物联网远程开发平台&lt;/a&gt;。目前已在人工智能小镇部署了150余种物联网设备，用户只需通过浏览器(WebIDE)即可进行云-边-端一体的物联网应用开发。LinkLab需要解决可靠设备管理、多环境高效在线编译、theia WebIDE高效定制、大规模虚拟场景仿真等关键问题。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;新闻&#34;&gt;新闻&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2020.02] 实验室LinkLab论文被ACM/IEEE IoTDI 2020录用！&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2019.12] 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/C-9ljT8BpRzcs6LerJWO8Q&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;实验室助力阿里云IoT助理工程师考试认证&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2019.11] 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://linklab.tinylink.cn/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkLab v1.1&lt;/a&gt;发布！LinkLab支持TinyLink、AliOS Things在线编程&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2019.10] LinkLab v1.0测试版发布！欢迎使用LinkLab.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2019.10] 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/SpU14B9pdX9Ik4w5ZnwSuw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkLab参展中国计算机大会CNCC 2019.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2019.06] 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.emnets.org/iotbook&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;《从创意到原型：物联网应用快速开发》新书出版！&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[2019.04] 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/K03k1yoDCdaNt82HVJyGxQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LinkLab参展2050大会.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;关于linklab&#34;&gt;关于LinkLab&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LinkLab是阿里巴巴-浙江大学前沿技术联合研究中心（AZFT）物联网实验室推出的物联网远程开发与实训平台。LinkLab平台为阿里云IoT工程师考试与认证提供关键技术支撑。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;linklab使用教程&#34;&gt;LinkLab使用教程&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://home.emnets.org:8888/linklab/tutorial00.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;入门教程：LinkLab用户系统和基本操作&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://edu.aliyun.com/certification/aca04&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;阿里云IoT工程师考试认证&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TinyEdge</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/tinyedge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/tinyedge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;港珠澳大桥是我国首座集桥岛隧一体的现代跨海通道工程，为了“用好管好”这座世界级的现代跨海通道工程，迫切需要推动桥岛隧跨海通道工程运维管理技术创新。本课题为国家重点研发计划课题研究内容。
课题研究复杂环境下低功耗广域网传输模型，提出抗干扰、自适应性强的传输机制；研究边缘计算负载动态迁移技术、以及边缘侧网络资源感知传感协同技术，通过在边缘侧对不同业务进行预处理，提高数据处理效率和实时性，并降低带宽与能量消耗；研究边缘侧多集群管理技术和支持多CPU架构、多运行时环境的轻量级编排技术，提高系统稳定性；研究支持多源异构数据处理的边缘计算系统架构，构建多类型边缘计算系统平台，形成基于边缘计算的海量数据采传收一体化技术方案，为桥岛隧巡检、维养设备以及边缘视频处理提供模型与算力支持，在台风等极端天气时提升响应速度。&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TinySim</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/tinysim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/tinysim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developing and experimenting IoT applications are still difficult and time-consuming, mainly due to their heterogeneous hardware and diverse software. In this work, we develop LinkLab, a scalable IoT testbed for heterogeneous devices. LinkLab not only supports running experiments but also supports remote development via a web-based IDE and remote compiling. By using a distributed architecture, LinkLab is a scalable, multisite, and multi-user IoT testbed, with fine-grained access control and a flexible naming mechanism. Currently, LinkLab is implemented with more than 150 IoT devices. The system has been published in ACM/IEEE IoTDI 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TinyLink</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/tinylink/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/tinylink/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TinyLink is a holistic system for rapid development of IoT applications. Developers write the application code in C-like language to specify the key logic of their applications, without dealing with the details of hardware components. Taking the application code as input, TinyLink automatically generates hardware configurations as well as the hardware dependent code executable on the targeted hardware platform. We have further extended our system to integrate cloud, device and client development in one piece of code, greatly accelerating the process for cloud-device integrated applications development. The designs and implementations have been published in ACM MobiCom 2017 and ACM MobiCom 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>低功耗无线</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/wireless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/wireless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent years have witnessed many low-power wireless technologies, e.g., ZigBee, Bluetooth, LoRa, etc. These heterogeneous technologies raised several important research issues, such as how to combat against cross-technology interference, how to perform cross-technology communication without a gateway, how to interoperate over a wide range of IoT protocols. In this study, we aim to address several key issues in this field. Initial works have been reported in IEEE ICNP 2018, IEEE ICDCS 2017 and IEEE TMC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>智能感知</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/sensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/sensing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Modern IoT and mobile devices are equipped with a rich set of sensors, including accelerometer, gyroscope sensor, IMU sensor, acoustic sensor etc. Even the wireless module, traditionally used for communication, can be used as a sensing module (i.e., wireless sensing). The ubiquitous availabilty of these sensors, as well as the advances in signal processing and machine learning, give us unprecedented opportunities to better sense the physical world and human beings. In this study, we will focus on innovative applications and intelligent sensing techniques based on IMU, WiFi and millimeter-wave. Initial works have been published in UbiComp 2018 and UbiComp 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosaic</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/mosaic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/mosaic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Air quality monitoring has attracted a lot of attention from governments, academia and industry, especially for PM2.5 due to its significant impact on our respiratory systems. In this work, we design Mosaic, a low cost urban PM2.5 monitoring system based on mobile sensing. In Mosaic, a small number of air quality monitoring nodes are deployed on city buses to measure air quality. We have deployed the Mosaic system in Hangzhou and Ningbo, China. We conduct research on system design and deployment issues as well as sensor data calibration. These works have been published in IEEE INFOCOM 2016, IEEE INFOCOM 2017, and UbiComp 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GreenOrbs</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/greenorbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/greenorbs/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SenSpire OS</title>
      <link>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/senspire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://www.emnets.org/zh/project/senspire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The development of a modern sensor network is difficult because of the long-term unattended operation mode, diverse application requirements, and stringent resource constraints. To address these issues, we design SenSpire OS, a predictable, flexible, and efficient operating system for sensor networks. We achieve system flexibility by providing a hybrid model for both event-driven programming and multithreaded programming. We have also designed an object-oriented programming language (CSpire) to enhance system usability and programming convenience. SenSpire OS has been implemented on three most commonly used sensor node platforms. The system is reported in IEEE TC 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
